

□ 657-229-5927 | ■ Izhoucs@gmail.com | ★ http://Izhoucs.github.io | □ Izhoucs | □ Izhoucs

Summary_

Seasoned full-stack software engineer with 8 years of industry experience, specializing in Java and JavaScript based web applications, passionate about new and cool open source technologies.

Skills_

JavaScript ES2015(ES6), TypeScript, Node.js, AngularJS, React.js, Dojo, jQuery, Grunt, Gulp

Web HTML 5, CSS 3, LESS, Bootstrap

Java EE, Servlet, JSP, JPA, Spring, Hibernate, Struts, Maven, Gradle, Junit, Mockito, Selenium, RESTful web services, SOAP web

services, WebSphere

DataBase Oracle, DB2, MS SQL Server, MySQL, Endeca

Methodology Agile, OOAD, Design Patterns, Functional Programming, Continuous Integration, TDD, BDD

Tools Bash, Git, IntelliJ IDEA, Emacs

Experience _____

SitePen

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2016-05 — Present

· Built enterprise web apps using popular frontend technologies.

Contributed to open source(Dojo, Dojo 2 etc)

eMids

 Senior Software Engineer
 2014-09 — 2016-05

· Designed and implemented from scratch an E&B Configuration Tool that help reduce dev cost dramatically.

• Worked on a few frontend apps powered by Angular.js and Java/C#.

Nike

 SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER
 2013-07 — 2014-08

• Architected and implemented the new RESTful search service based on Spring MVC.

- Designed and implemented the Nike Merchtools.
- Helped set up Java Coding Standards.
- · Mentored less experienced team members.

Oracle (f.k.a. Micros-Retails)

- Implemented new features of XStore POS by writing Core Java code.
- Wrote GWT code for Xcenter Admin app.
- Wrote unit tests, integration tests and Selenium functional tests.

Asiainfo

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2009-07 — 2010-10

• Developed a reporting tool that supports multi-dimensional query and analysis.

• Implemented frontend functionality and backend Java services.

Tarena Tech

 SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN
 2008-10 — 2009-07

• built a few small Java based web apps.

Education

Maharishi University of Management

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science 2011-02-2013-11

June 7, 2017 Liang Zhou · Résumé

Shaanxi University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Engineering (BE) 2004-09 — 2008-06

Oracle

Sun Certified Java Programmer(SJCP) 2009-05 — Present

Honors & Awards

2015-09 Rising Star Award, eMids

2015-06 **Top Performer Award,** eMids